{"name": "62D 2009 Aisa", "questions": [{"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "1. The polynomial x2 - 16 factors as:", "choices": {"A": "(x + 4)(x + 4)", "B": "(x - 4)(x - 4)", "C": "(x - 4)(x + 4)", "D": "(x - 16)(x - 16)", "E": "(x - 16)(x + 16)"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "2. At a certain store, 3 bottles of water and 2 bags of chips cost $8.00. At the same store, 2 identical bottles of water and 3 identical bags of chips cost $7.00. How much would 2 of these bottles of water and 2 of these bags of chips cost at this store?", "choices": {"A": "$6.00", "B": "$3.00", "C": "$2.00", "D": "$1.50", "E": "$1.00"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "3. Tom has scores of 0, 6, 7, 8, 10, 10, and 10 on his science lab reports, which are all equally weighted. Which of the following is closest to the mean of his science lab report scores?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "7.3", "C": "8", "D": "8.5", "E": "10"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "4. What is the value of 3k2 - k + 2 when k = -3 ?", "choices": {"A": "-28", "B": "8", "C": "32", "D": "80", "E": "86"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "5. The expression 2y - 5 + 3y is equivalent to which of the following expressions?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "-y - 5", "C": "y - 5", "D": "5y - 5", "E": "6y - 5"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "6. What is the value of f(3 ) when f(x) = 2x2 + x + 3?", "choices": {"A": "12", "B": "18", "C": "21", "D": "24", "E": "30"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "7. The filling machine in a cereal factory fills 1,200 boxes of cereal every 5 minutes. Which of the following proportions can be solved for t, the number of minutes it takes the machine to fill 2,000 of these boxes of cereal?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "8. If a farmer originally had a supply of 1,450 bushels of corn and sold 580 bushels, what percent of her original supply did she sell?", "choices": {"A": "40%", "B": "58%", "C": "60%", "D": "67%", "E": " 87%"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "9. Pierre is sewing a clown outfit for a customer and needs a button. In his button bag, he has 8 yellow buttons, 4 orange buttons, and 6 red buttons, all the same size. Pierre will take one of these buttons out of the bag at random. What is the probability that the button is an orange button?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "10. Given x3 = 38.7, where x is a real number, the value of x is between which 2 consecutive integers?", "choices": {"A": "3 and 4", "B": "6 and 7", "C": "12 and 13", "D": "38 and 39 ", "E": "57,960 and 57,961"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "11. When the number 0.00735 is expressed in scientific notation, it is represented by 7.35 x 10x. What is the value of x?", "choices": {"A": "-5", "B": "-3", "C": "-2", "D": "2", "E": "3"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "12. Terri plans to tile her kitchen floor and needs to know the area of the floor to get an estimate of how much the project will cost. The figure below shows her kitchen floor with dimensions given in feet. What is the area of Terri's kitchen floor, in square feet?", "choices": {"A": "132", "B": "225", "C": "245", "D": "270", "E": "303"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "13. What is the midpoint of the line segment with end-points (-2,8) and (6,2) in the standard(x,y) coordinate plane? ", "choices": {"A": "(-4,3)", "B": "(2,5)", "C": "(4,-6)", "D": "(4,10)", "E": "(8,-6)"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "14. A government class has an enrollment of 26 students, all of whom are juniors or seniors. There are 4 more juniors enrolled than seniors. How many seniors are enrolled in the class?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "11", "C": "15", "D": "17", "E": "22"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "15. In basketball, when a player makes a basket, his or her team scores 3 points if the ball is shot from a distance of more than 6 meters from the basket, 1 point for a free throw, and 2 points for all other types of shots. During a recent game, Will's team scored a total of 26 points on Will's baskets, which consisted of 4 free throws and more 3-point baskets than 2-point baskets. How many 3-point baskets did Will make during the game?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "5", "D": "6", "E": "7"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "16. What real value of x satisfies the equation  ?", "choices": {"A": "16", "B": "64", "C": "80", "D": "160", "E": "320"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "17. The time that a storm will take to reach a town can be predicted by using the formula , where t is the  time, in hours; d is the distance, in miles; and s is the speed, in miles per hour. A storm was 200 miles from the edge of Burlington at 10:00 A.M. and was traveling directly toward Burlington at a speed of 25 mph. According to the formula, at what time will the storm reach Burlington if the storm does not change course or speed?", "choices": {"A": "8:00 P.M.", "B": "6:00 P.M.", "C": "4:00 P.M.", "D": "2:00 P.M.", "E": "11:00 A.M."}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "18. A line segment and a plane can have at most how many points in common?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "1", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "Infinitely many"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "19. In the figure below, AE and BD intersect at C, and BD is perpendicular to both AB and ED. The length of AB is 10 feet, the length of BC is 40 feet, and the length of CD is 120 feet. What is the length, in feet, of DE?", "choices": {"A": "10", "B": "30", "C": "35", "D": "40", "E": "60"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "20. The figure below consists of a geometric shape and a line through point P. If this figure is rotated 180\u00b0 clockwise about point P, which of the following is the figure's image?(Note:The rotation is in the plane of the figure.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "21. To the nearest centimeter, what is the perimeter of the trapezoid shown below?", "choices": {"A": "48", "B": "51", "C": "54", "D": "56", "E": "60"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "22. A rotating sprinkler sprays the entire area of a circular region with water out to 7 feet in every direction, as shown in the figure below. What is the area sprayed, to the nearest square foot?", "choices": {"A": "22", "B": "38", "C": "44", "D": "154", "E": "616"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "23. A surveyor needs to know the width of a flood control channel. From point A, she walks 100 feet to point B and sights to point C, as shown below.From this sighting, the surveyor finds that the measure of \u2220ABC is 50\u00b0. Which of the following is closest to the width, in feet, of the flood control channel?(Note: sin 50\u00b0 \u2248 0.766; cos 50\u00b0 \u2248 0.643; tan 50\u00b0 \u2248 1.192) ", "choices": {"A": "64", "B": "77", "C": "119", "D": "131", "E": "156"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "24. What is the greatest common factor of the following 3 monomials?                   20x5y3, x2y10, 14x8y8", "choices": {"A": "x2y3", "B": "2x8y10", "C": "14x8y8", "D": "  20x5y3", "E": "20x8y10"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "25. Use the following information to answer questions 25-27.Two friends,Chris and Pat, joined a new 14-week program to lose weight through dieting and exercise. Chris set a goal to lose 10 pounds every 4 weeks, for a total of 35 pounds, while Pat's goal was to lose 7 pounds every 4 weeks, for a total of 24.5 pounds. Chris began the program weighing 200 pounds, and Pat began the program weighing 187.5 pounds.25. If both Chris and Pat met their goals exactly, how many more pounds would Chris weigh than Pat at the end of the program?", "choices": {"A": "0", "B": "0.75", "C": "2", "D": "3", "E": "10.5"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "26. Use the following information to answer questions 25-27.Two friends,Chris and Pat, joined a new 14-week program to lose weight through dieting and exercise. Chris set a goal to lose 10 pounds every 4 weeks, for a total of 35 pounds, while Pat's goal was to lose 7 pounds every 4 weeks, for a total of 24.5 pounds. Chris began the program weighing 200 pounds, and Pat began the program weighing 187.5 pounds.26. Chris lost 5 pounds during the first 2 weeks of the program, but lost only 3 pounds during the next 2 weeks. How many pounds of weight loss per week will Chris need to average during the remaining 10 weeks to meet the goal of losing 35 pounds during the program?", "choices": {"A": "2.7", "B": "3", "C": "3.5", "D": "4", "E": "5"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "27. Use the following information to answer questions 25-27.Two friends,Chris and Pat, joined a new 14-week program to lose weight through dieting and exercise. Chris set a goal to lose 10 pounds every 4 weeks, for a total of 35 pounds, while Pat's goal was to lose 7 pounds every 4 weeks, for a total of 24.5 pounds. Chris began the program weighing 200 pounds, and Pat began the program weighing 187.5 pounds.27. Suppose that Pat loses 1.75 pounds each week. At the end of week K, where k = 1, 2, ... , 14, he calculates 1.75 pounds as a percent of his body weight and records the percent as P(k). Which of the following best describes the values of P(k)?", "choices": {"A": "They increase as k increases from 1 to 14.", "B": "They decrease as k increases from 1 to 14.", "C": "They increase as k increases from 1 to 7 and decrease as k increases from 7 to 14.", "D": "They decrease as k increases from 1 to 7 and increase as k increases from 7 to 14.", "E": "They are constant as k increases from 1 to 14."}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "28. The circle below has its center at O, and points A and B lie on the circle. The length of AO is 4 inches, and arcmeasures 112\u00b0. What is the measure of \u2220ABO ?", "choices": {"A": "17\u00b0", "B": "34\u00b0", "C": "45\u00b0", "D": "56\u00b0", "E": "68\u00b0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "29. The functions f(x) = x(x + 3)(x + 1)(x - 3)(x - 2) and g(x) = -x(x + 3)(x - 3)(x - 1) are graphed below in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane. How many solutions are there to f(x) = g(x)?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "3", "C": "5", "D": "6", "E": "Infinitely many"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "30. Three lines intersect, as shown below, with angle measures as marked. Which of the following is NOT necessarily true?", "choices": {"A": "v + y + z = 180", "B": "v + w = 180", "C": "w + x = 180", "D": "x + z = y", "E": "y + z = w"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "31. The sum of the solutions for the equation (x + 2)(x - 3) = 0 is:", "choices": {"A": "-6", "B": "-5", "C": "5", "D": "-1", "E": "1"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "32. If 2x - 3(2 - x) = 19, what is the value of 2 - 3x?", "choices": {"A": "73", "B": "41", "C": "23", "D": "-13", "E": "-73"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "33. In the figure below, lines k and m are parallel, lines n and p are parallel, and lines n and q are perpendicular. lf the measure of \u22201 is 37\u00b0, what is the measure of \u22202 ?", "choices": {"A": "37\u00b0", "B": "43\u00b0", "C": "53\u00b0", "D": "63\u00b0", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information."}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "34. What is the measure, in degrees, of an angle of radians?", "choices": {"A": "10\u00b0", "B": "20\u00b0", "C": "30\u00b0", "D": "60\u00b0", "E": "120\u00b0"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "35. If 23 \u00b7 42 = 2x, then x = ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "5", "C": "6", "D": "7", "E": "12"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "36. What is the slope of the line 6x - 4y = 8 in the standard (x,y) coordinate plane?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "37. What is the set of all integers in {5, 6, 7, 8, 9} that are also in the solution set of 2x + 7 &lt; 3x + 1?", "choices": {"A": "{5, 6, 7} ", "B": "{6, 7, 8, 9}", "C": "{7} ", "D": "{7, 8, 9} ", "E": "{9}"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "38. A rectangular painting is 22 cm wide and 28 cm tall. It will be framed with a mat. The mat forms a uniform border 4 cm wide around the painting. A piece of glass, cut to size, will cover the painting and mat exactly. What is the area, in square centimeters, of the piece of glass?", "choices": {"A": "148", "B": "464", "C": "616", "D": "1,080", "E": "2,464"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "39. In the figure below,is a semicircle. What is the perimeter of the figure, in feet?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "17 + 13\u03c0", "D": "30 + 13\u03c0", "E": "34 + 13\u03c0"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "40. In the figure below, \u25b3EFG has angles and a side length as given. What is the measure, in feet, of EG ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "9", "D": "6", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "41. A state's department of motor vehicles wants to issue licenses that contain 3 of 24 letters (the 26 letters of the alphabet except for O and I), followed by 2 of 10 digits. No single license should use any letter or digit more than once. Two such examples for licenses are AXL34 and ALX34. When the restrictions are followed, how many different licenses are possible?", "choices": {"A": "263 \u00b7 102", "B": "243 \u00b7 102", "C": "223 \u00b7 92", "D": "26 \u00b7 25 \u00b7 24 \u00b7 10 \u00b7 9 ", "E": "24 \u00b7 23 \u00b7 22 \u00b7 10 \u00b7 9"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "42. In rectangle ABCD below, AB is 5 inches long and BC is 4 inches long. If point P lies on AB, what is the area of \u25b3PCD, in square inches?", "choices": {"A": "5", "B": "9", "C": "10", "D": "20", "E": "Cannot be determined from the given information"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "43. The 13th, 14th, and 15th terms of an arithmetic sequence are 61, 65, and 69, respectively. What are the first 2 terms of the sequence?", "choices": {"A": "4, 8", "B": "9, 11", "C": "9, 13", "D": "13, 15", "E": "13, 17"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "44. What is the area, in square centimeters, of parallelogram ABCD shown below?", "choices": {"A": "30", "B": "40", "C": "50", "D": "55", "E": "60"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "45. What is the smallest positive number that is a multiple of both 12 and 90 ?", "choices": {"A": "2", "B": "6", "C": "180", "D": "360", "E": "900"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "46. When the original price of a sweatshirt is discounted by 25% and the discounted price is then reduced by 10%, the resulting price is the original price discounted by what percent?", "choices": {"A": "15%", "B": "17.5%", "C": "25%", "D": "32.5%", "E": "35%"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "47. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, approximately how many coordinate units is (5,3) from (9,-3)?", "choices": {"A": "3", "B": "4", "C": "7", "D": "10", "E": "14"}, "correct": "C"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "48. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, what is the equation of the line that is parallel to the y-axis and contains the point (-3,2)?", "choices": {"A": "x = -3", "B": "x = 2", "C": "x = 3", "D": "y = -3", "E": "y = 2"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "49. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.The DigiPhone Company advertises the following calling plans:49. Tanisha is on the $89.99 plan, and Suki is on the $119.99 plan. To the nearest cent, how much more is the before-tax charge per minute for 600 minutes on Tanisha's plan than for 1,000 minutes on Suki\u2018s plan?", "choices": {"A": "$0.03", "B": "$0.12", "C": "$0.13", "D": "$0.15", "E": "$0.75"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "50. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.The DigiPhone Company advertises the following calling plans:50. Luis chose the S149.99 plan. There are certain months when he uses more than 1,400 minutes of calling time. For a month in which he uses x minutes of calling time, where x is an integer greater than 1,400, which of the following expressions gives the amount, in dollars, of his bill before any taxes are added?", "choices": {"A": "0.20x", "B": "149.99 + 0.20x", "C": "149.99 + 0.20(1,400 - x)", "D": " 149.99 + 0.20(1,400 + x) ", "E": "149.99 + 0.20(x - 1,400)"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "51. Use the following information to answer questions 49-51.The DigiPhone Company advertises the following calling plans:51. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the points (600,  89.99), (1,000,  119.99), and (1,400,  149.99) are collinear. DigiPhone wants to offer a new plan that includes 400 minutes of calling time for a charge in line with those of its other plans. If $z represents the before-tax charge for this new plan, what should be the value of z so that (400,z) is on the in same line as the points representing the other plans?", "choices": {"A": "26.67", "B": "44.99", "C": "53.33", "D": "59.99", "E": "74.99"}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "52. Whenever cos x \u2260 0 and sin x \u2260 0, the expression sec2 x + tan2 x is equivalent to:", "choices": {"A": "1 + sin 2x", "B": "1 + cos 2x", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "53. The shaded portion of one of the following graphs is the set of all x and y such that -1 \u2264 x - y \u2264 1. Which one?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "54. In the standard (x,y) coordinate plane, the graph of the equation x2 + 3y2 - 4x + 12y = 0 is:", "choices": {"A": "a point.", "B": "a line.", "C": "a hyperbola.", "D": "a circle.", "E": "an ellipse."}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "55. When x is divided by 8, the remainder is 5; and when y is divided by 6, the remainder is 1. If each of x and y is at least 20, what is the minimum value of x + y ?", "choices": {"A": "40", "B": "46", "C": "52", "D": "54", "E": "60"}, "correct": "B"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "56. The numbers a and b are real numbers and |a| \u00b7 b = a \u00b7 |b|. Which of the following must be true about the relationship between a and b?", "choices": {"A": "a = -b", "B": "a = b", "C": "ab \u2264 0", "D": "ab \u2265 0", "E": "a = 0 or  b = 0"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "57. If k is an integer and k &gt; 2, which of the following expressions is equivalent to ?(Note: For any positive integer n.   n! = (n)(n-1)(n-2)\u2026(2)(1). Hence 5! = (5)(4)(3)(2)(1)=120.)", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "-1", "D": "0", "E": "1"}, "correct": "A"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "58. The lengths, in inches, of all 3 sides of a triangle are positive integers, and 1 side is 7 inches long. If the area of this triangle is positive, what is the smallest possible perimeter for this triangle, in inches?", "choices": {"A": "9", "B": "10", "C": "14", "D": "15", "E": "21"}, "correct": "D"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "59. The square of a certain positive integer is k. Which of the following expressions is equivalent to the square of the next integer greater than that certain positive integer?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "k + 1", "C": "k2 + 1", "D": "(k + 1)2", "E": ""}, "correct": "E"}, {"title": "", "name": "", "article": "", "question": "60. In the figure below, . What is the value of h ?", "choices": {"A": "", "B": "", "C": "", "D": "", "E": ""}, "correct": "D"}]}